In this short video, I'm going to
demonstrate how you can access your
assessment files and once completed, then
upload them to your tutor for marketing.
So when you're on the My Study
page, as you can see, you will have
your course and your assessments.
Now to access the actual assessment
materials, you click on the course itself.
So the link takes you through
to the IT User Skills course.
And as you can see, there are some
buttons along the top there, which
is where you can V-mail your tutor,
your action plan, which will have
your submission dates, your journal,
so any of the information that you've
recorded as you've worked through
the course will be stored in there.
The group forum where your tutor
will post some information relating
to the various units and also some
additional links to support you.
Your portfolio, so all of the
work that you've completed
is stored in your portfolio.
So you always have access to that and
the actual progress on the course.
For each of the units, you just need
to click on one of the three links that
you are presented with on this page.
So unit one is word processing.
Unit two is presentation software
and unit three spreadsheet software.
There are actually four units within this.
The other unit, which is Improving
Productivity Using IT is embedded
within each of these units.
So there are elements within
word-processing, presentation
and spreadsheet software.
So you do complete four units,
but it is only three assessments.
So to access your assessments,
if you click on the unit one Word
Processing Software link, it will
drop down and you will see each of
the sessions, you can access the
course materials and the assessment
by clicking on each of these links.
So for example, if I click on session one,
which will take you through the welcome
pages, and then the first session of the
course, if I click on page seven, I can
access the assessment files from there,
which will take me to the assessment page.
Alternatively.
I can download the assessment files
directly from clicking on that link
and at the bottom beneath session
six, there is the unit one assessment.
I would always recommend downloading
the unit one assessment or unit two
assessment or unit three, before
you start each of the units, which
means that you can then work through
the assessments as you work through
each of the sessions in the course.
So if I click on the unit one
assessment, this then takes me to
the download page and I just simply
click on the download unit one
assessment, and that will be saved in
a suitable location on the computer.
You also need to download
these additional six files.
As you work through the assessment,
you will create a range of documents
and all of the information required
to assist you in completing these
documents is provided in these downloads.
So if you download the assessment and
the additional files and save them in a
suitable location, that will be everything
you need to complete the assessment.
So once you've downloaded the
assessments and you've worked through
each of the sessions and completed
the assessment fully, you then need to
submit that to your tutor for marking.
To do that, you need to go
back to the My Study page.
And as you can see on the My Study
page I have now activated the IT
User Skills unit one assessment link,
the PowerPoint and the spreadsheet
links aren't there yet because they
don't become active until you've
actually downloaded the assessments.
It's important to submit your files using
this link as if you V-mail them to your
tutor, you are outside of the system.
This way, the system tracks your
progress and it will indicate to your
tutor that you have submitted work for
marking and then your tutor will attach
feedback to that, which will indicate
whether it was a pass or a resubmission.
This is the only way that
you should submit your work
to your tutor for marking.
So to do that, you simply click
on the link and that will open up,
very similar to V-mail, and all I
need to do there is to browse to
the files that I need to upload.
So as you can see at the moment,
there is only one window there.
So if I click on browse, And then I
navigate to the location of the files,
which is the word processing files.
So there are five files that I've
created for this, which is the form
final, form mail merge, newsletter
amended, and the assessment document.
So I just simply click on the first
one and that will attach that file,
but I now need to add additional files.
So I just simply click on that
link there and then browse and
then attach the  second file.
Click add additionall information,
browse add the third file, add additional
information, browse, newsletter
amended, add additional information,
browse and attach the assessment.
So you have now attached
all five of the documents.
It's very important that you do attach
all five files that you've completed.
In presentation there are three
files and in Excel there are two
files, it's important that you submit
them otherwise your tutor will not
be able to fully mark your work.
So once I've done that, you can
pop a message into your tutor.
And then once you're happy, you
can click on send assessment
and that will then disappear.
And as you can see, the link has
been used, so it is no longer
available on the assessment page.
Your tutor will then send you
feedback and then if there are any
additional actions, the assessment
link will become active again.
So once you've done that, you can then
go on to session two or unit two, and
then unit three, again, simply click on
the unit two assessment link, download
the assessment and the relevant files.
Once complete, you would then go to
unit three, download the unit three
assessment files, and that will then
allow you to download everything.
And as I say, once you've completed
every session and you've completed
all the assessment materials.
You simply go to the My Study page.
And as I say, once they've been
downloaded, they won't become active
until they're downloaded, but once
they are, it will allow you then
to submit your work to your tutor.
If you do have any difficulties,
the first point of call is to V-mail
your tutor and explain the situation
and they will be able to assist you.